JISHNU CHAKRABARTI

OTHER CONTACT DETAILS

https://twitter.com/jishnuch



engineerjishnu.wordpress.com



https://github.com/engineerJishnu



Muscat, Sultanate of Oman.

SUMMARY

A Printing Engineer by qualification and is passionate in writing programs for an Open Source Hardwares like Raspberry Pi, Arduino using C, C++ during my free time - all by self learning.

The competencies attained during my journey in Printing Industry for past 24 years are:-

- Estimations,
- Inventory Management,
- Technical Service,
- Production Planning & Co-ordinations,
- Outsourcing local and International vendors,
- Cost control,
- Quality control,
- Team management skills,
- Ability to communicate with technical and business colleagues.

I am self driven and motivated individual with an attitude of constantly learning, improving and solving. I have fluency in English and is comfortable in interacting with multiple levels of organization, management and staff from different locations.

I am looking forward for a platform in your organization to shift my career from printing to a software engineering field to fulfill my passion. I am committed in putting my sincere efforts in learning, performing and delivering which in turn will help an organization to achieve its business goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS - SELF ACQUIRED

PLATFORMS

☐ Proficient with Linux, Windows & Mac OS.

SOFTWARE

☐ Proficient with MS Office.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

☐ Familiar with C, Python, C++ (All by self learning).

PUBLISHING IN WEBSITE

☐ Familiar with Wordpress, GitHub.

HARDWARE

☐ Familiar with Raspberry Pi, Arduino, BeagleBone Black and Udoo X86.

EDUCATION

☐ 1994 Graduated from Pune University, India - Bachelor of Engineering (Printing Branch)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

☐ Since 2015 onwards.

STORES MANAGER at Joint Stock Company - Computer Stationary Industry SAOG & Oman Printers & Stationers Limited Co LLC.

• Muscat, Sultanate of Oman.

□ 2012 to 2015.

ESTIMATION, PLANNING & OUTSOURCING (Local & International) at Oman Printers & Stationers Limited Co LLC.

• Muscat, Sultanate of Oman.

■ 2003 – 2012.

ASSISTANT MANAGER – PRODUCTION COORDINATION at Oman Printers & Stationers Limited Co LLC.

• Muscat, Sultanate of Oman.

2002 – 2003.

ASSISTANT MANAGER (SHEET FED OFFSET PRINTING) at Twenty First Century Printers Limited.

Silvassa - India.

2000 -2002.

EXECUTIVE - CUSTOMER SERVICE & DEVELOPMENT at Sicpa India Limited.

• Mumbai - India.

□ 1998 – 2000.

SENIOR EXECUTIVE - PRODUCTION at Borkar Packaging Pvt limited.

• Daman - India.

	JU Bo	1996 – 1998. NIOR EXECUTIVE PRODUCTION at rkar Industries Pvt limited. Goa - India.	
	EX at (1995 – 1996. XECUTIVE PRODUCTION COORDINATION Colour Cartons Limited. Mumbai – India. 1994 – 1995. IANAGEMENT TRAINEE at Colour Cartons imited. Mumbai – India.	
	M/ Lir		
HOBBIES			
	pro per doc	tening to music from vinyl, Computer gramming and documenting them in my sonal diary. Now, I have started cumenting in Wordpress and have started ring my codes in Github.	
LANGUAGES KNOWN			
	☐ English (can speak fluently, read and write) Hindi Bengali.		
PERSONAL DOSSIER			
		Date of Birth 29 th August 1972.	
		Gender Male.	
		Permanent Address 7 /1 Mahendra Road, Bhowanipur, Kolkata (Calcutta), Pin Code - 700 025 India.	
		Marital Status Married & having a daughter of 17 years and currently residing with me in Muscat.	